<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on The Culdesac</title>
    <link>//www.shiyankoh.com/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on The Culdesac</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//www.shiyankoh.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Forest City: A Ghost Town Finds Its Residents with the Network School</title>
      <link>//www.shiyankoh.com/blog/forest-city-a-ghost-town-finds-its-residents-with-the-network-school/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//www.shiyankoh.com/blog/forest-city-a-ghost-town-finds-its-residents-with-the-network-school/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is a certain irony in finding one of the most vibrant communities I&amp;rsquo;ve encountered in what was designed to be a ghost city.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I recently visited &lt;a href=&#34;https://ns.com&#34;&gt;Network School&lt;/a&gt;, Balaji Srinivasan&amp;rsquo;s experiment in intentional community and co-living, now housed in the shells of Forest City.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Forest City sits just across the Causeway from Singapore, a massive development built by Country Garden, one of China&amp;rsquo;s largest property developers. The original vision was audacious: 30,000 residential units on four man-made islands, a gleaming city for the future. Country Garden pre-sold apartments, collected deposits, and then ran headlong into the twin headwinds of China&amp;rsquo;s property crisis and Malaysia&amp;rsquo;s political sensitivities around foreign ownership. What emerged was a monument to overreach—pristine towers, empty streets, and the eerie quiet of a place built for hundreds of thousands but inhabited by almost no one.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chef&#39;s knife? Or Kiwi peeler?</title>
      <link>//www.shiyankoh.com/blog/chefs-knife-or-kiwi-peeler/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//www.shiyankoh.com/blog/chefs-knife-or-kiwi-peeler/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A chef&amp;rsquo;s knife can do almost anything in the kitchen — chop, slice, dice, even peel if you&amp;rsquo;re determined enough. A kiwi peeler? It does exactly one thing, and only if you happen to have a ripe kiwi handy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Lately, I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about this knife vs. peeler analogy as a way to make sense of the explosion of AI applications, startup ideas, and even how we teach kids math. There&amp;rsquo;s a big difference between building general-purpose tools and building hyper-specific ones. And in a world where flexibility and adaptability matter more than ever, this distinction is becoming critical.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How much reality should you give a child?</title>
      <link>//www.shiyankoh.com/blog/how-much-reality-should-you-give-a-child/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//www.shiyankoh.com/blog/how-much-reality-should-you-give-a-child/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re a parent, or involved with small children through blood or friendship, chances are you&amp;rsquo;ve been forced/privileged to observe a performance or two. Perhaps it was a song, something approximating a sporting event, or the performance of a musical instrument. Unless your child is a prodigy, most of these early performances are adorable but not particularly outstanding.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Recently, my daughter was upset because she felt that at an impromptu post-meal performance in front of family and friends, adults were more interested in their phones than listening to her sing. So - what is one to do? On the one hand, we all wish adults were less glued to their devices, on the other, to really break through and capture someone&amp;rsquo;s attention you need to think about your audience and what is compelling for them. Singing a few songs doesn&amp;rsquo;t cut it in this day and age!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Welcome 2024!</title>
      <link>//www.shiyankoh.com/blog/welcome-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//www.shiyankoh.com/blog/welcome-2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A new year is always a great opportunity to reflect and set some goals - inspired by Der Shing&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://limdershing.blogspot.com&#34;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt;, thought it useful to jot down priorities and give myself a chance to check back in a year to see how well I did against my stated intentions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;priorities&#34;&gt;Priorities&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Health&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Improve sleep quality&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Improve VO2max&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Relationships&lt;/strong&gt; - Quality time focus&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kids&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;K&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Parents&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Work&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Time blocking more aggressively — Using &lt;a href=&#34;https://flow.club&#34;&gt;Flow Club&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Building more process/automation/async comms — Using &lt;a href=&#34;https://async.com&#34;&gt;Async&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href=&#34;https://loom.com&#34;&gt;Loom&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Community Building&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A year of podcasting</title>
      <link>//www.shiyankoh.com/blog/a-year-of-podcasting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//www.shiyankoh.com/blog/a-year-of-podcasting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Late last year, Jeremy Au invited me to do a weekly podcast with him, riffing on the latest news in the Southeast Asia Tech scene. Now I love listening to podcasts (Acquired, Odd Lots, Stratechery), but I had some trepidation about being so out there with my thoughts in public. I figured it would be a good way to challenge myself. (good &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/kevinleeme/status/1742270859753201691?s=20&#34;&gt;tweet&lt;/a&gt; from Kevin Lee on getting over this fear)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Early entrepreneurial efforts</title>
      <link>//www.shiyankoh.com/blog/early-entrepreneurial-efforts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//www.shiyankoh.com/blog/early-entrepreneurial-efforts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of my favourite childhood memories was picking fruit from my best friend&amp;rsquo;s yard, loading up her red radio flyer wagon, and wandering around her neighbourhood selling oranges to her neighbours. We had no guidance on pricing, and no real goals other than wanting to be able to buy snacks at the pool snack bar we often frequented. Other revenue generating activities in my youth included raking leaves ($0.25 per giant trash bag) which seemed way more fun than waiting for my grandma to reward me for good grades. I&amp;rsquo;ve often wished I&amp;rsquo;d been encouraged to pursue some of these earlier entrepreneurial endeavours more, vs. being directed to study harder!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Day of School</title>
      <link>//www.shiyankoh.com/blog/first-day-of-school/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//www.shiyankoh.com/blog/first-day-of-school/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always loved first days - of school, work, trips - it is a moment bursting with possibility and anticipation. (and of course the school canteen, the best part of Singaporean schools)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today was my daughter&amp;rsquo;s first day of primary school - first grade for my American readers. It was utterly adorable with all of the children lined up for assembly in the school hall with the parents seated behind the kids. This was a day reserved for the P1 students - a nice touch I thought to make the whole experience less overwhelming for the kids. They took the time to explain their two week orientation, and how they were focused on 3 specific outcomes: 1) making friends, 2) understanding teachers&amp;rsquo; expectations, &amp;amp; 3) getting comfortable with the new environment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Silicon Valley: A Discovery Operating System</title>
      <link>//www.shiyankoh.com/blog/understanding-silicon-valley-a-discovery-operating-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//www.shiyankoh.com/blog/understanding-silicon-valley-a-discovery-operating-system/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article was published as part of the book &amp;ldquo;America: A Singapore Perspective&amp;rdquo; edited by Tommy Koh and Daljit Singh. The full book can be purchased &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/America-Singapore-Perspective-29-Writers-ebook/dp/B09MTR2CDK&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Koh Shiyan and Karen Tay&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chances are, you can access this article from a smartphone right now: a device that was unimaginable for most just twenty years ago. In milliseconds, it serves up real-time directions, messages, music, entertainment and distraction for six billion people around the globe.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On building communities</title>
      <link>//www.shiyankoh.com/blog/on-building-communities/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//www.shiyankoh.com/blog/on-building-communities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been building communities all my life. In the beginning, it was accidental - I noticed that most groups were willing to do things if someone (anyone!), provided a small amount of direction, &amp;ldquo;Hey guys, let&amp;rsquo;s go to the beach and do X, Y, Z,&amp;rdquo; vs let&amp;rsquo;s all stand around discussing things we could do for 30 minutes, with everyone politely deferring to everyone else and no decision being made.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metrics - what matters and why (to a pre-seed investor)</title>
      <link>//www.shiyankoh.com/blog/metrics-what-matters-and-why-to-a-pre-seed-investor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//www.shiyankoh.com/blog/metrics-what-matters-and-why-to-a-pre-seed-investor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The idea of metrics for a pre-seed startups can feel rather oxymoronic; what does it even mean to have metrics when the business is so early? To add to the confusion, investors say conflicting things about the types of metrics they are looking for.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Forget the investors for a second - as a founder, what do YOU want to know about your business? You are smart and talented and could be doing a million other things. What things should you be looking at to validate your own ideas?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Race, power and what we can do about it</title>
      <link>//www.shiyankoh.com/blog/race-power-and-what-we-can-do-about-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//www.shiyankoh.com/blog/race-power-and-what-we-can-do-about-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re watching the news, and face it, who isn&amp;rsquo;t, it&amp;rsquo;s disheartening to watch what&amp;rsquo;s happening in the US right now.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, we sent a note out to our portfolio founders:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sitting here in Southeast Asia, which has it&amp;rsquo;s own troubled history with race, colonialization and conflict, it&amp;rsquo;s been so hard to watch what&amp;rsquo;s been happening in the US.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Not only are we still dealing with the surge of cases of the coronavirus, which we know is affecting so many of your businesses, but in addition, you may have seen in the news a lot of racially charged incidents that also happened this week. This spans from a police officer murdering weaponless George Floyd to a woman threatening to call the police on a Black man who was birdwatching and rightfully trying to tell her to put a leash on her dog. These are not one-off cases, but just the latest in a series of incidents where Black Americans are the subjects of casual police brutality. For those of you who are not based in the United States, a lot of this may sound completely senseless. I, too, couldn&amp;rsquo;t explain any of this to my kindergartener. It just doesn&amp;rsquo;t make any sense.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
